when you're creating gadgets of any kind
you want to know the the individual
pieces like you can't solve the puzzle
without knowing what your puzzle pieces
are right and I think it's really
important to understand what the
different components are because then
you're hacking when you're away from
your computer then you can go
[Music]
for best part ofing when you can just
you know critical things right
[Music]
dude hey what's up critical thinking
family uh today we have a a dear friend
of mine his name is Kieran most of you
probably already know of him but his uh
hacker handle is monkey and uh we'll get
into a little bit more of his story
later but uh for now you know the ritual
we have to jump straight into a bug so
what did you bring us today Kieran
I have three bugs what um because yeah
are you trying to one up all our
previous
guests yeah we we'll uh jump into the
the bugs I guess I do a lot of client
side stuff um so hopefully that
translates well on the audio format
because you know how client side can be
well our listeners have heard Justin
describe enough bugs and if I get
confused ask questions I'll play the The
Listener here yeah um so first bug was
account takeover via post message on uh
public program that I can't name for
obvious reasons but um what made it
really interesting was like the sheer
number of um gadgets we had to bring in
I was doing this with my friend animes
who's a he's Australian researcher cool
so uh we we spent like I think like a
week or something on this but basically
did it pay off the idea was yeah we we
got high Bounty from it so that was that
was awesome nice um but there was
several pieces to this bug um the core
of it was that there was uh an xss in a
chat widget that was on the page and
that had a gadget that let you leak the
uh the hre of the parent so this this
chat widget was in a KN frame and the
exploit we had was to leak the O code
from the the parent URL mhm it had this
like logging thing that would like send
the the they would read the parent H ref
and so um I need to like remember which
so basically the this chat widget itself
had um this you could send a post
message to it and it would like render
the the URL you give it in like an
iframe source so you could send it a
JavaScript protocol and it would pop xss
in the context of the chat widget
um
and this this they had like four or five
if frames on this page like the
victim.com had like four or five if
frames right and
so uh the problem was that they had an
origin check um but you know
that allows custom JavaScript for their
custom domains oh yeah of course so I
could get a window reference by hosting
custom JavaScript on it is origin M and
do window. open to the victim page and
then you could send a post message and
bypass the origin check because it's
like it it was from a origin so it would
yeah it was listed yeah right and so
that was great except the oo flow had
Coupe it had cross origin opener policy
and I think Justin's discussed this
recently but it is a huge pain uhhuh for
for post message bugs um but
then discovered that you could fixate
the state and what that would let you do
would it would like jump you one step
ahead in the O flow mhm um so it wasn't
it wasn't like slash authorize or
whatever it was like the next step over
which didn't have Coupe so we would like
generate the oath State on our end
fixated in the victim and it wasn't tied
to the the victim session or anything or
any of that so we could generate a state
and have it be
valid that would then redirect to um the
page with the the if frames and stuff
and with these kinds of bugs you need
like a dirty dancing uh Gadget of some
kind because you need the code to be
unused and to sit in the URL right MH so
what I did here I double URL encoded a
hash fragment so on the first redirect
oh nice it would decode once on the
second redirect to victim page it would
decode twice but it would put the code
parameter in the hash fragment when it
did that so it would be unused so so it
wouldn't be processed but you could
still snag it exactly so the full chain
was like window. open to this fixated
state which would redirect with the
double Ur encoded hash fragment and put
the code in the URL then I'd send a post
message to one of the chat widget frames
but that wasn't the one that had the
logging mechanism so I would like I
frame hop over from the the first frame
to the second frame CU they're the same
origin and when they're the same origin
you can uh change the JavaScript and
that you can overwrite the Dom yeah so I
would like hijack the frame with the
logging thing I would trigger the log so
the parent HF would leak to the the
Salesforce chat and then I would uh
exfiltrate from there because that's
just excess in the chat and they they
fixed that otherwise I wouldn't talk
about it but yeah did you have a um did
you have like the whole thing automated
and set up or did you just like record
it once for the demo and submit it or or
do you have it like replayable so they
could so they could redo it yeah I I had
a so this took so long to get through
triag I ended up writing this code
snippet that would generate the state on
my server yeah and then the JavaScript
on would get the fresh state from my
server each time to generate the PC it
it was a ni really big PC yeah yeah
that's cool though that's amazing all
right bug number two bug number two was
I got account takeover without being
logged in client side um which seems
impossible but so there was a
unauthenticated uh csti so client side
template injection it was in angular but
the problem was it only existed in the
context for you weren't logged in um
yeah so yeah this sounds very
interesting so did is it like a did it
execute and then wait and then when they
did log in like XEL to you tell us how
this works so the key here was that they
had a mirror domain that was not the
same uh domain as as the one we exsess
that had the same cookies but oh of
course same origin policy applies so you
can't just reach over and read that's
that's not how it works but what they
did have was they had this this is
another post message thing where they
had a post message listener that would
uh send the the users's credentials mhm
to to the parent but they had frame
ancestors and what that means is unless
it was in one of the uh Pages owned by
the company they wouldn't let you do
that post message sending the cookies to
the parent
MH um and the other problem was that if
you received the cookies in an
unauthenticated scenario like in the
csti page it would like log in and
redirect so that that would break the
whole chain as well because you know you
can't do anything so what I ended up
doing here
with the xss i
iframed the the same page with the csti
so like example.com iframed example.com
okay and then I purged the Dom because
they're the same Origins so you can just
wipe the Dom MH and in that I put an
iframe with the other uh page that had
logged in but that was a different
domain okay that would meet the criteria
for the frame ancestors but because I
purged the Dom the JavaScript that would
redirect no longer existed right so then
I could trigger the chain where I send
the post message get the creds which
would go to my purged one and that would
xfill to to my origin so you had you had
a template injection based xss the top
then I had an if frame right on
example.com right and then I had the
other origin at the very right right
right the one where they're actually
logged into yeah and I purged the middle
one so it wouldn't redirect but it would
keep the
because of the frame ancestors you could
kind of like reach into the to the one
they were logged into to grab the creds
and then exrate them yeah the frame
ancestors
whitelisted the the csti page but by by
putting by purging the D I don't trigger
the the code that would cause the
redirect and break everything so so I
guess this would always work right
anytime you want to kind of reach across
with a post message from um one domain
when you can't you could potentially use
that same xss to do what you did in most
of those cases right you could wipe the
Dom make an ey frame if you've got a
scenario where the Dom has code that
breaks something mhm you can iframe
itself cuz you know even with um most
frame restrictions it's even if it's
same origin you can still if frame
yourself and you can just Purge the Dum
and like keep keep the benefits of the
same origin but not the problems with
any code on it right any code that's
like kind of a blank slate like a
playground almost yeah that's awesome
all right and your third one is a server
side bug right yes because as much as I
like client side I don't want to just be
a CLI side guy you know we should we
should have alternated it we should have
put the server side in the middle to
kind of balance it out there probably
probably for any for any listeners that
aren't gone yet tell us about the
servers side bug yeah so this was during
my like 100 hour challenge I did for the
newsletter last year that did really
well by the way yeah it went quite well
I was pretty happy with it um and so
basically
there was a a proxy like proxy API mhm
and it had the classic URL parameter um
I did actually pop ssrf on this URL
parameter but that's not what this bug
is this is a different bug in the same
place uh so I was just playing around
with it as you always do when you find
something strange mhm and I put a
relative path because that's always
worth checking not just https but just a
slash sure and it gave me this error
that was like J protocol not allowed and
I was like this is really weird like
what is this and you weren't passing a
you weren't passing a draw file to it or
anything no it was just a slash it was a
URL equals slash so I was like this is
super strange um and then I did like SLX
and it gave me class path resource does
not exist mhm now when you hear class
path immediately it's like Java yeah
because Java is the most common for
classes um and so I asked pmh who is
like a god at Java stuff he's written a
book on Spring security so he's like my
go-to friend for for the server side
stuff and he was like oh maybe it's this
um and
basically uh if I put the class path
protocol which is apparently a protocol
in Spring it didn't error which meant
what it was doing was it was loading
whatever file I gave it inside the
certain function in Spring that was made
for loading
jars interesting so were you able to
write a jar file into that no B okay
this this was unfortunately a low bug it
was just really really cool okay so he
was like try like slash meta INF which
is like right pretty much a default file
in all all J's and that gave me the same
error J protocol not allowed so by
playing around with that I figured out
what it was doing was if the file name
existed it would give me J protocol not
allow and if it didn't exist it would
say class path resource not found MH so
then I could just use this to fuzz the
entire like the file names of all the
source code they had all their jars
that's funny so it's basically like a
file name disclosure yeah but I couldn't
load them and I couldn't like get RC or
anything because I couldn't actually it
was just for loading up the jars and not
executing them once you knew what those
files were that existed did you try to
browse to any of them I guess you could
have done the same thing if the if you
didn't have that Gadget where you just
tried to browse to them but because they
were server side it wouldn't load
anyways but yeah yeah but I could like I
used the program name and like fuzzed
all the like the the file names and
stuff so I got quite a lot of
information for Just differentiating
Between Two error messages yeah that's
cool you know so yeah it was a fun one
nice dude well to give people a little
bit of different backstory um on kind of
your history and our history um yeah
Kieran uh and I met in a really cool way
actually so I was working at appomni and
we were trying to hire another
researcher for the labs Team U which
you've probably heard me talk about
before that's where I worked with Aaron
Castello and uh I hop on a call and uh
this guy's face is sitting there and
he's like hey do you do bug Bounty or
are you an ambassador are you an
ambassador for hacker one I was like
yeah I am and he's like I am too and so
Kieran
is yeah yeah that was like the second
batch so there was only like 20
something ambassadors yeah yeah it was a
pretty small crowd and then obviously
the bug Bounty space is pretty small so
uh anytime you meet somebody in bug b
you know it's like a there's a kindred
spirit
there yeah you like oh I'm also an
ambassador for for Kentucky and I was
like what yeah did you yeah you didn't
know that right you didn't like pre-
look me up or anything both ho had no
idea we just kind of happened to tease
it out which is
cool yeah so Kieran then of course I
lobbied hard to get him hired and ended
up getting hired at appomni and how long
did you work there with us for two years
yeah it was about two years I know you
were kind of like full-time then
part-time then uh do like you were doing
schooling and everything else I was
shuffling it with University as well so
yeah yeah uh um so kind of sweet we got
to work together for for a while um and
that probably honestly what made us
become even better friends and now we're
both full-time bug Bon Hunters so we're
still colleagues uh we we get to collab
a lot and uh we're actually currently
we're currently hacking on something
this week with our buddy Archangel
Douglas day um and I think you were
gonna mention that he had just launched
a newsletter right yeah yeah um I I
think he's getting more into his uh his
creative side now um so he launched a
newsletter called Angel drops so yeah
and if you just go to douglas. day you
can click like newsletter there on the
left
you yeah his domain is so cool I know I
always mention that on the podcast but
uh if I I wish I could get first name.
last name I don't think cter is gonna be
a TLD so you might not be able to do
that you could get hacker someday you
know yeah yeah I think me Justin and I
might have missed down recent one but
yeah if I could get like Joseph t.
haacker where it's my name with the dot
after the first letter of my last name
that'd be pretty sweet yeah um yeah tell
us a little bit I mean just if there's
like anything we don't need to get into
your whole backstory but if you think
there's like kind of any anything
interesting or inspiring to upand
cominging bug Hunters I mean you're
pretty young and you've already been at
a few live hacking events and um you
know you seem to know everyone else in
the industry um yeah I guess just tell
us a little bit about kind of that how
you got there and if anybody you know
doesn't know you and you want something
want them to know something about you um
in case you can't tell from his accent
kieron is in from Ireland I can I can
run through how I got into bug Bounty
and stuff sure for sure yeah so the the
main motivation was that I just had no
money in college um and I was like I I
need money I was pretty good at writing
code in the past mhm um like doing
Python and stuff so and then I found bug
benty I think it was through stocks
videos yeah what did you see like maybe
ran across on YouTube yeah yeah yeah I
was like doing the same stupid like how
to make money online crap that oh you
know a lot of us go through at some
point and and then I found stocks videos
and he had like life hacking event uh
Vlogs right yeah had you done any CTF
stuff so do you think the algorithm knew
you might be interested or at that point
you had not I have no idea at some point
I came across them and then I I was
watching his videos like this is so cool
like I really want to go to one of these
things and so from there I think I
joined the bug crowd Discord server and
I met my friend Mikey Mikey 96 who's
been like friend since the very start of
my security career yeah um and
and so from there it just kind of went
through the same cycle of like reporting
crap bugs into reporting good bugs into
reporting like fun chains now yeah um
and but my first Venture into security
was very much bug Bounty and not CTF
like I I took the unusual path of bug
bounty to CTF rather than the the
reverse yeah so you did some stuff at
your University right once you were kind
of into bug bounding into hacking you
kind of uh kind of spearheaded that
there at your University right yeah so I
exactly so I got into the hacker one
ambassador program um pretty early on in
in my bug benty journey and a bunch of
us got invited to h172 two years ago
that was in or yeah more than two now
that's
2022 and while I was there um I went for
a breakfast I think it was in Denny's in
Vegas with a bunch of other hackers
classic and then Justin was there and he
realized I could speak Japanese so he
just pulled me aside and just yeah Kier
is half Japanese like his mother is
Japanese for yeah for context I I live
in Edinburgh in Scotland but I'm half
Irish half Japanese I grew up in Ireland
and so the minute Justin realized that I
could speak Japanese his like inner
wanting to practice his language skills
came out and Yeah from there I think he
just have introduced me to like a lot
more hackers and stuff so that was a a
huge huge moment for me honestly yeah I
did I plus one you to that 702 I feel
like I may have but uh I don't know it
also but that was shortly after I
started working at appomni so we were
hanging out for a bit for sure at the
event yeah cool yeah and then um yeah so
and then obviously I of late kind of a
cool thing we're going to both going to
be at Google's Tokyo um live event
coming up in April which which should be
really cool again with Justin um yep and
so uh hopefully we'll find some great
bugs I think it's AI Focus so um I was
going to mention that I know I do want
to like Circle back to hearing what you
and Link are cooking up but um uh I know
that you also kind of have a pinent for
for AI hacking you and I have looked at
a bunch of different AI products um was
there anything you wanted to say kind of
in that regard that you thought was cool
or that you uh have been doing oh sorry
and did I even mention that kieran's a
researcher at at uh cddb yeah so Kieran
Kieran is one of a handful of people
that uh just brought on to the ctbb
research team so it's it's him Matan be
um Kevin who we heard from last week um
or I guess it'll be two weeks ago by the
time this goes out um no I think friends
as well yeah uh who is it this hako Haku
piku and fr are also yeah FR and Haku
piku yeah so I guess yeah maybe cover a
little bit of what you're doing with the
research lab and then the AI hacking
stuff sorry yeah yeah sure um I think
the research lab is very Cent side
focused at the moment um I mean the
other guys are geniuses they're finding
some really cool stuff but um I I have
one bit of research I want to talk about
today very briefly um because it's a
piece of research that I just don't have
the the time to work on myself now so
I'm hoping someone will listen to this
and like look at this behavior I'm about
to describe and you know take it
somewhere and do something this is a
free Bound for the listeners right it is
um and so and it's server side so this
is a a nice bit of variety um but to do
it websockets uh and
so I was messing with websockets
recently enough a few months ago just
because I think they're very
underappreciated not just from a bug
Bounty standpoint um but from just a
general research standpoint because they
are a whole other protocol yeah they're
hard to understand I would say a lot of
bug Hunters just ignore them and the
other thing is they're asynchronous so
they're a lot harder to work with than
HTTP which is like pretty sequential
when you're dealing with it most of the
time mhm and
so um and what yeah websockets are often
susceptible to the same kinds of bugs
because you're if you think about it um
where it sits in like uh an an
infrastructure it's just a protocol so
it's just a means of communicating
information so when it hits the server
it's going to have the same problems
right right still needs oth still needs
you know it's still using IDs to access
data so you can still have idor still
have off bypasses still have all the
even even xss right because it's often
taking that content and rendering on one
side or the other it could exactly it
really could um I think I think space
raccoon had something like that on Zoom
or something but yeah there's a bunch of
stuff that can happen with them and
people are just afraid of websockets so
they don't they don't go looking um and
so I was messing around with uh these
websockets on one of my programs and I I
was
I assumed that
um it would it would follow the spec and
of course it never follows the spec
right and and I found this really weird
Behavior where so with with websockets
uh it's a pretty
simple way to to the way you upgrade to
a websocket connection is quite
straightforward you send um an upgrade
request which is a HTTP
request um with certain certain request
headers that tell the server I want to
upgrade my connection to a websocket
right and then from that point on the
server will interpret the rest of the
data uh you send as as websocket frames
um and then it's completely switched to
the websocket protocol you initiated you
get a one1 back right yeah you exactly
you 101 is like the successful
connection response and from that point
the server assumes you're on the
websocket protocol you're no longer on
HTP in any capacity mhm um and while I
was messing with this I was for some
reason I had the stupid idea to send
like body uh like a request body with
with the connection request yeah and
what that ended up doing um the server
interpreted the request body as a
websocket frame yeah I remember you
telling about this yes yeah yeah
complete nonsense it's it's nonsense
because so what I I figured out what I
think is happening is
the server sees the first request as
like 101 MH you it it'll process the
requests in order so it looks at the
first request it says okay we're now
websocket connection and then it looks
at the second bit of data I sent and it
says okay this is a websocket frame this
should be this should be the first frame
of the websocket exactly so what you can
do it's HTTP body right yeah you can you
can control the op codes like normally
with a websocket connection it has the
op codes and stuff at the top it has
like a a header and then it has a body
that's like what each frame looks like
and so normally when you're sending
stuff in a websocket you can only
control the message because that's the
up codes are settings they're like this
is text Data this is binary data right
that kind of thing but with the
pipelined frame you can control
everything because it's just taking raw
raw binary information so I like managed
to construct the byes of a valid frame
like a very minimal one and it was
accepted by the server yeah yeah um and
this is still your connection so it's
not that impactful but what's really
strange is that it also responded to
transfer encoding chunked which is a way
you can send post body information yeah
that opens up a lot of doors yeah do you
think that that's because sometimes it's
like it would be possible to send a
websocket request that's too large and
so it's actually going to do a similar
thing that it does with HTTP where it's
basically breaking up into multiple
websocket requests the so there is a
thing called fragmentation in websockets
um there there's an up code you can set
that breaks up your websocket data into
like smaller chunks it says this is a
fragment this is a fragment yes and so
on so that's actually already handled by
the websocket protocol it doesn't make
sense why transfer encoding would used
it it makes me think that they layered
it they basically like shimmed it in
they shimmed in websocket report or
sorry websocket
uh like the feature basically they
shimmed it into an HTTP stack and so the
HTTP stack is still reading HTTP headers
for some reason yeah it's something like
that um yeah I think it's pipelining so
pipelining is my guess of what's
happening right um and
so the the significance of transfer
encoding chunked is that this is like
one of the the requirements for request
smuggling so you could have this insane
theoretical attack vector
where if you send content length and the
server is ignoring transfer encoding
reading content length there's a nonzero
probability that you can smuggle
websocket frames via request smuggling
exctly other users right yeah which be
crazy or get theirs back right that
that's always the impact is that
basically you can send requests users or
get their data back yeah right right and
so I would love if someone investigated
this because it makes no sense why
transferring coding or pipelining should
work in a websocket context but it does
and I've tested this across multiple
different websocket uh implementations
yeah AKA Port sger team if you're
listening maybe do a deep dive
here yeah that's really cool man yeah I
remember you doing that initial research
and you know I'm really interested in it
because I feel like so many different AI
uh chatbots use websocket for streaming
back and forth um you know sometimes
they don't sometimes they use like a
single big long HTTP chunk thing that
gets put in as as it's received but a
lot of times it'll switch to websockets
um how does the like once you get
upgraded is there just like a single key
that access that
controls um kind of authentication there
for websockets that just gets passed
with every
request yeah web sockets don't have
authentication like implemented really
you have to do that yourself in every
because it do because it's like each
connection is just from you to them yeah
right yeah um but aot of the time they
do say origin checks on where where
you're initiating the connection from so
cross site websocket hijacking isn't
that common anymore um it's pretty it's
pretty difficult to find attack vectors
I think of of the implementation these
days yeah but there there is absolutely
more there so you know it's a bone a
bone to look at really yeah that's cool
well if if anybody figures this out or
messes with it definitely uh message Us
in the in the critical thinking Discord
Channel either me or Kieran or or Justin
or somebody I would love to to get a
closed loop on this where actually
speaking of closed Loops this is not in
our notes Kieran but there are three you
there you have had three separate times
in the last year when you have either
thrown out a bone in your newsletter and
you've closed the loop yourself or
someone else has I think it's been you
every time right so if you can remember
what these three examples were and
they're not program specific all I know
is I feel like there's been three
separate times where I'm messaging you
and you're like yeah actually this
vulnerability we're working on right now
I just happened to mention nine months
ago in my newsl so if you're not
subscribed to Monkey hacks you need to
go subscribe to it but yeah there was
that piece of research you were working
on with a few other researchers um and I
had like found this your final payload
in the Wild by pure chance and written
about it yeah like months before yeah
yeah yeah yeah yeah that was the
actually I talked about that on I think
as I talked about that as my
vulnerability um with Justin on the pod
it was uh what was the name of that
formatting
language no ampscript ampscript yeah it
was it was the ampscript vulnerability
so people should go back and find that
but what were the other two if you don't
mind me asking oh there was one xss
payload that I like used with Douglas
yes yeah yeah there was an xss payload
that was theoretical that you had
dropped in your notes months ago and
then it was the exact payload character
for character that you all used to pop
this thing yeah yeah I don't remember
the last one but it's it's it's a you
know subscribe to the newsletter that's
a take here I'm going to share my screen
so people can see it and because it
helps uh the producers with uh knowing
this so I'm going to share
screen Chrome tab there we go so yeah
this is this is uh this is kon's uh um
newsletter slash um Wow website because
it's uh beehive so it's kind of both and
you can go back and read all of his uh
posts by going here I think
yeah so he he publishes pretty
frequently um on his on his email list
um as you can see he's an enjoyer of
some some uh AI art as well but uh K
kind of details his journey that's one
thing that I think is neat you know
everyone's newsletter has a little bit
of a different spin kieran's newsletter
is you know it's got plenty of good
content and news like other ones do like
he cover he he puts like the most recent
stuff in here but um more than that he
also talks about his journey you know
like places he's went with like actual
kind of uh photographs and stuff and
then you know his kind of Zero to Hero
Journey as well is kind of captured in
here so that's sweet yeah I think having
that personable aspect to bug Bounty is
super important as well because that's
how I got into bug bounty in the first
place was like stalk doing these Vlogs
and adding that personal element is what
kept me engaged with everything yeah
kind show the lifestyle right yeah yeah
and one of them was H1 4420 that he went
to and then I actually went to that in
2023 which was like full circle moment
right like you watch this and then and
then I I was at the event and I found
his Stock's old videos and I was like oh
my God I'm like I'm here I made it yeah
yeah yeah exactly it does feel like it
was for me and I'm sure it is for lots
of other hackers it does feel like the
uh Allure of going to a live event is
like such a strong motivator for like
getting good and like finding a lot of
bugs so if you're out there and you're
you know and that's that's the dream
then I would just say keep with it you
know hold that in your minds and and use
it to kind of uh work hard yeah and I
mean we can touching on the upcoming one
with Google I think there's going to be
a big overlap between client side and AI
hacking
because like the AI has to interface
it's it's implemented in some way it's
interfacing with the website um via
client side things so a lot of the time
if it's a chat a chat window that almost
always uses post message so or even from
the exfiltration standpoint once you've
got a prompt injection can you render
elements that expose the website to like
cross- site leaks you know are there eye
frames that are created that let you say
count the number of ey frames and get
information about the the victim in that
way so it's something I really think is
going to be super important now in the
next few years yeah I mean just as
another little bone to The Listener
didn't you find a way like it's wasn't
you you actually didn't fully close the
loop so it's probably still V in a
specific product that's out there you
found a way to inject messages kind of
into the into the chat stream with the
AI but um but there was just nuances
there that didn't let you fully close
the loop so people should definitely
like to post message bugs injecting or
reading
messages yeah yeah I can't say too much
about yeah that one because it's not
fixed yet but yeah hopefully hopefully
fully crap I I did have a an AI bug uh I
think yeah I had an AI bug a while back
like a few months ago where um there was
like this document templating system so
I HD The Prompt injection inside the
template and you could put this on a
Marketplace so the like attack scenario
was that the victim would download my
template and write their stuff and they
would like select all the text and do
something with it with the inbuilt AI in
the text editor MH and I mean this is
this is all like one ecosystem so the
mer was same that's what you're expected
to do yeah yeah yeah it was a SAS
platform that had all this stuff so um
the attack scenario was that the victim
would like take my template um and
because my my template had invisible
text that was like white text when they
run the the AI on it it would do prompt
injection um and this thing had two
calls built in so this was like
basically able to even have right access
if you'd misconfigured your AI in that
way that's awesome yeah yeah I mean that
scenario where basically you're editing
an object that is inside of the
ecosystem with a prompt injection
payload it's something that I put in my
guide that I'm about to release on U
basically how to be an AI hacker so um
very cool attack
scenario um so Justin I think
interviewed Kevin last week uh and so
one thing I wanted to do well actually
before we before we Circle I think we're
going to cover a little bit of news as
the point that I'm building to but I
actually wanted you to uh get a chance
to mention what you and Link from Buck
are working on yeah so my friend link
and I we've been working on a project
for where we want to connect he's like
kind of over community at bu Crow right
yeah yeah he he does community
management at bug CR um and we've been
launching or you know working on this
this idea where we want to connect
hackers with companies um so hackers who
want to find work with companies who are
looking for security Talent um and we'll
always take more candidates right so if
you're looking for security work just
feel free to reach out um and send your
CV and stuff and we'll see what we can
do sweet um cool and then uh yeah so
basically whenever we have a lot of
guests here on ttbb we uh don't often
touch on the news and the News kind of
builds up so there was some uh some some
some cool uh news almost all these are
AI related just because that's what I'm
most interested in
so I'm sure there's some non air related
news too I think even
um I think Fort swiger actually said
like keep your eyes out we have some
research dropping soon I don't know if
they actually posted that or not but um
I saw I saw a tweet about that recently
um cool yeah so the things that I wanted
to Showcase one was grock 3 um let me
see if I can share my screen yeah it's
default in grock 3 sweet so I can do
this I'm G to share my screen um so
grock 3 is pretty much state-of-the-art
based on everyone that I'm following and
one cool thing about grock is that it's
much less uh like it's more jailbroken
kind of by default it's much less likely
to do reject them rejection so if you
are a security researcher and you're
looking for like the best in class and
you also don't want it to reject you
let's see if we can get it to generate
some payloads generate 15 different
unique xss payloads that would execute
in different
context for my
research all
right first of all it called me out on
my typo on how I spell generate but yeah
and then you know it actually uh it
generated 10 that's 10 oh here it goes
keeps going um but it's pretty quick and
also uh actually I'm going to say don't
put them in code blocks we'll see if we
can just pop a xss right here uh yeah
it's not going to do it but um sure
didn't deep seek have a xss yeah I'm
sure it did honestly deep had a lot of
issues going on with it but uh this is
always one trick you know if it's in
code blocks like this whatever's on the
front end that is converting this uh
markdown into
uh HTML for the rendering you know you
won't ever get these to pop but then if
you just say you know don't put it in a
uh markdown code block then sometimes
these will actually pop whenever you're
when you're you're hacking on
applications but yeah so pretty cool I
just want to mention this because it is
like kind of state-ofthe-art you can use
this think mode to make it think longer
and deep search for it to like actually
go away and do research for you and um
if you're you know a person who's doing
a lot of hacking and you haven't decided
which kind of AI chat bot to subscribe
to I think that um both chat GPT and
Claude will still kind of give you some
rejections they're pretty easy to work
around if you just you know say you have
authorization to test on it but I wanted
to mention that Croc 3 dropped I think
far's been pretty uh generous with me
recently cuz we we had that uh we F SQL
injection yesterday and I was messing
with the payloads and stuff in GPT 4 and
it was just not complaining it was
giving me all the stuff I wanted so
that's awesome
um yeah I mean I I haven't had any
issues either especially if you set some
sort of system prompt I'll very
frequently use Misti app and I can just
set like the system prompt for all the
different models and if you just say hey
you're a security researcher um yeah I
think I'm might have mentioned that
before but I can share my I think I can
share that app here in just a minute
actually here I'll just go ahead and do
that so I'll stop sharing this um let me
make sure I don't have anything
sensitive pulled
up I do actually so let me start a new
chat
conversation yeah so I'll share screen
and window Misty yeah so I had mentioned
this before um in like tweet thread but
in case people didn't see that so this
is called Misti and uh it's like MST Y.A
not not sponsored by them or anything
but my favorite thing is that you can
add split chats and then you can change
these models so you know I could use
Sonet here 40 here and I use I love
Gemini flash so Gemini 2 flash here and
then you just click this sync button so
you can say like like I'm a security
researcher and I'm trying to figure out
how um csrf Works can you show me a you
know a safe I'm just doing this so it
doesn't reject me U benign csrf example
HTML in a code block um you know and so
you get to see all of their answers kind
of simultaneously it's so it's really
nice because if you just like care if so
you have like your keys in here so
you're getting charged for these tokens
um but you know Flash 2 is really cheap
honestly son is pretty cheap and so is
40 but this is really nice because if
they if you're hacking on something and
you want like a bunch of like you know
example payloads or example on ideas of
what to hack or whatever it's just
really nice to be able to run three at
once and kind of get the wisdom of the
crowd or be able to like if this one
generates something good and these two
don't you can copy it and run it or
whatever and they have different
strengths as well don't they so yeah
exact yeah exactly so sometimes one
might work well and another one you know
might not work or whatever so um yeah
okay I use AI quite a bit with my
workflow these days like for reversing
like obfuscated JavaScript I have a a
heavily modified version of the FR
rosen's post message yes Chrome
extension that lets me take the The
Listener logic and I click analyze with
AI in my little modified extension and
it will like run it through chaty PT for
uh for bugs to see if there's any like
issues with that post message log
basically to see if there might be a
vulnerability in it exactly exactly like
is there any JavaScript syncs that
enable xss and are they reachable and
all this stuff so I have like a because
obsidian allows you to do deep links I
have a button that will generate the the
Merd down document with the results like
report document yeah the output the
output of the of the analysis goes
straight into your obsidian into my
notes exactly pretty fun yeah that's
really cool um sweet yeah actually here
I'll show my screen but do you want to
talk about what we're going to share
next about what space raccoon has been
doing yeah sure um so he's written a
book um from day zero to zero day which
I'm sure is no easy feet um I looked
into it a little bit uh it goes pretty
much through his uh how to be a zero day
hacker how to be how how to find zero
days
effectively yeah um of which he found a
long time yeah he's a he's up there in
terms of hackers that are very respected
so you know definitely worth reading I
would say even on the Gareth Hayes
JavaScript for hackers level like
mandatory reading yeah space Ron
basically does almost everything in his
life with Excellence uh if you've seen
his blog post he has a few famous blog
posts that are um extremely thorough and
very good and uh uh I'm pretty sure he
would just dominate at anything he did
like if he I think he he's been working
for he works for the I think the
government in his country right I'm
trying to remember where it is yeah it's
in Singapore
right um and I'm pretty sure over there
he is not able to keep above a certain
amount of income from bug Bounty and so
he actually donates a ton of money away
oh W um that he makes above and beyond
like that cap that he's allowed to make
based on their their government like
with him with the way he's employed and
stuff and so he's also an extremely
generous person and uh I'm a big fan but
I'm sure this book's fantastic you
should definitely check it out yeah he's
not active on the the life hacking event
circuit anymore is he no I think and I
think it's just because he is really
busy at work I know he basically was
like dominating bug Bounty and then he
was like oh I'm just goingon to go
figure out how to you know be like a
full-blown awesome like low-level tester
and then I I think that's when he did
like his oscp and when he started
working for their government and then um
I see and then um that's when he started
doing like the kind of the zero day
research like looking at like binary
exploits and I don't know I don't know
what his uh focus is at the moment but
yeah yeah I feel like there's a bunch of
hackers like that who've like maybe were
super active two years ago and now we're
running companies and doing their own
thing and stepped away from the bug
Bounty scene a little bit you been
you've been in the circuit for a long
time res for me took me a long time to
go fulltime uh appomni kept R me back in
uh so I'm only just now getting on my
full-time track you know so so glad you
did make the jump as well um because
it's great to have you have you fulltime
bug Bounty now yeah we can actually chat
a lot more we're we're more like
colleagues uh and we get to get to
collab on a lot more yeah yeah I would
say app's uh it really changed the way I
thought about bugs a lot um because
appomni for I mean if you've listened to
Aaron's episode recently you probably
know is SAS SAS security um and mostly
focusing on things like security
misconfigurations um but to find those
you really need to change the way you
think about SAS platforms like as a
system and that had a really big effect
on my bug Bounty like in the past two
years yeah I mean just just like even
knowing the differences between like hey
this is misconfigured and so it's not a
vulnerability for the platform but a lot
of the customers are really going to
consider this extremely vulnerable and
so we and so it's both farmable but it's
really impactful both to the companies
and the end users like if you're an end
user you don't want your you don't want
your pii leaked all over the Internet
and so it's like even though it's not a
vulnerability to the platform it's
really you have like you said you have
to shift your mind into realizing that
these configurations still could be
vulnerabilities for the companies yeah
and I think at a certain level of
hacking um or like practice with hacking
there's like a mental jump you make
where everything you're looking at is
like this big mess and it suddenly turns
into this organized system right like
the way you model it in your head and
know Douglas is really really good at
this which is why he's so success
with his uh with his access control and
idors is just modeling a system because
that's all bug benty is you're looking
at this website and you're taking out
the individual pieces and you're looking
at the flaws and how they interact with
each other that's right um and so making
that jump was like me mentally app Omni
was like instrumental in my own
development of making that mental jump
yeah I I mean I think the salary work
can be really beneficial for people on
lots of different levels you know if
you're if you're a triage you're going
to get access to a ton of things but
even if you're just a developer if you
know doing software engineering whatever
you're building you're going to like
very quickly become like a pseudo expert
at and so then that will help you
understand systems like that so much
better exactly um and to Circle back to
AI again AI is also another piece in the
bigger system so uh I think threat
modeling properly has really helped me
in the last few months because I never
used to do
it now I do you sometimes actually think
about like you like either whenever
you're not actively at your computer
you'll do or sometimes even when you're
sitting there you'll kind of threat
model the different paths to attack
right yeah um I think a lot of why we
say spent like 10 hours just looking at
the documentation and stuff is so when
you're creating gadgets of any kind you
want to know the the individual pieces
like you can't solve the puzzle without
knowing what your puzzle pieces are
right and I think it's really important
to understand what the different
components are because then you're
hacking when you're away from your
computer then you can go for a walk and
you can turn over the the threat model
in your head and then you can yeah look
for a bugs it's like when you're popping
a bug in the shower you're just thinking
about it and you're like oh that's what
it is yeah exactly if if you don't
understand how they're interacting your
brain can't work it out exactly exactly
uh and I it'll be the same for Google
I'm going to go and look at the
different pieces AI is just another
another puzzle piece I need to
familiarize myself and then look at how
it's interacting with things yeah been
clarifying my thinking a lot on that as
I've been writing this how to be an a
hacker post and um and I think the
reason why is kind of hard to model it
is because I think things like prompt
injection uh don't fit the normal
buckets for vulnerabilities and so the
way I the way I lay it out in the post
and I'm just going to mention here on
the Pod because you know a lots of
people won't see it or won't read it and
I think it'll be really useful is like
prompt injection itself can be a
delivery mechanism for normal
vulnerabilities like some of the
vulnerabilities that I've found in the
past few weeks have been like you know
uh some some sort of way to get the um
the AI agent or the AI chatbot to
basically respond with an xss payload in
the victim's browser and so in that
instance the vulnerability is still xss
when they sanitize that the
vulnerability goes away but prompt
injection is just the mechanism for it
whereas at the entry point yeah yeah
exactly whereas if it is actually um a
prompt injection that's leading to a
tool call in the user's browser that's
uh popping like the thing that you
mentioned the vulnerability itself is
actually the prompt injection like you
have to either rearchitecturing
needs to like have to have human in the
loop uh approval for any actions it's
going to take those are the only two
fixes like there are other mitigations
like you can use a model that's less
likely to be prompt injected you can
like look for you can like have some
sort of model classifier that's like
looking for text that's trying to
persuade the model to do something but
there's no fix for that like the
vulnerability itself is prompt injection
whenever like the the bug you describe
basically right it's like where you put
a promtion payload in the document and
then that's used in context of doing a
tool call later there's no um there's no
like other vulnerability it's like
prompt injection is the vul but then in
my xss example prompt injection was just
the vehicle so like if you can kind of
separate out it's like hey for some
things I'm going to be using prompt
injection as a vehicle to find
traditional vulnerabilities and the
other case I'm G to actually try to
exploit uh The Prompt injection itself
as a vulnerability and so I think that's
kind of interesting the way it can be
either or I have I have a story about
that actually um that you'll probably
enjoy I don't remember if I've told you
this so yeah it'll be a fun one um so
I've done I've done quite a bit of
traveling like in the last two years or
so yeah um and on one of those trips I
went to Japan to do a lot of just solo
travel um cuz I I really enjoy traveling
and so while I was there I made a friend
who's from tastan I don't remember his
name but I just remember he's from
Tajikistan yeah and he was actually a
PhD in ml and like llm stuff that's cool
um and so he was telling me that the
research he's doing uh and he was
presenting at this conference in Tokyo
was uh effectively planting an llm bomb
so it was going to be it was if you
poison the training set mhm to only
trigger this malicious action on certain
key words right then the model gets
shipped and then someone says the
trigger word which is like right you
know pulling the pin out of the it's
some token that's never used or a string
of tokens that are basically never used
until you're the person want toly and it
would just you know quote quote unquote
explode and the malicious malicious
action would be would be undertaken um
but this was like last year so it was
very much Cutting Edge when when he was
telling me about it yeah that's cool
yeah so i' I've seen something uh
similar to this there was a research
paper that came out that did something
similar the issue is like one thing
that's like really hard about this
is it's um it's really hard to know what
the tool calling infrastructure on the
other side will look like like sometimes
it's JavaScript sometimes it's like Json
output related and you won't even know
the names of the function calls and so
like it requires a lot lot of really
strong foresight I think that the best
way or like the most likely way this
would maybe occur in the wild is if it's
like some sort of like pseudo classifier
where it's using an llm but it's like um
it's having to Output like false or true
on like a lot of data um and it's a
situation where it's like kind of
mission critical that it gets it right
and then you basically have a keyword
that will always return true or always
return false depending on what your what
your goal is and so yeah yeah and so
like let's say you have this big piece
of text and you know that a classifier
is going to be operating on it to decide
if it's let's say if it's a prompt
injection payload right and this this
classifier is really good so much so
like the whole world's kind of trusting
it or something but then if you put in a
single string it will actually always
make the model output true or false you
know I think in those kind of scenarios
it's it's more malleable because like a
true or a false can be used in a lot of
different situations so planning like a
true bomb or a false bomb kind of in the
training data where you have a token
that will always make the output be true
or FAL or make it much more likely I
think it's like a malleable exploit that
might actually be valuable whereas if
you have it output you know Json that's
like make uh you know take this action
to do this thing it's like the systems
that are going to use it by the time the
model's out will probably have change
their architecture five different times
and the key value pairs that are needed
will change and so it's like a lot
harder to exploit right yeah I I think
he was talking about this like evil mode
so the training itself would like turn
on the evil mode oh gotta so it kind of
like jailbreaks it yeah in a sense yeah
yeah that's interesting I mean I suppose
if you have a universal Jailbreak in
that scenario you could like get it to
list its own tool calls and go Rogue but
yeah exactly yeah if you could plant
like a universal transferable jailbreak
that'd be
amazing yeah I'm sure the anthropic bug
Bounty would be uh more than happy to
take one of those yeah yeah they from
the recent challenge actually that's a
little bit of news they their um their
challenge where you had to like get past
the eight levels of of breaking uh was
finally won by a person I think they
ended up paying out like three people
that all won um a lot of people are
upset that it was basically like free
labor kind of in a similar vein to how
sometimes bug Bounty is viewed so we
don't have to get into the to the
nuances of that but I'm I'm glad that
the that the large companies do have bug
Bounty programs so anthropic and um open
Ai and Google all have bug Bing programs
in fact actually a lot of people might
not know Twitter has had a long-standing
bug bny program so X has a good one and
their their new plat form I think if you
go to gro.com or x. I think it's x.
there's like Gro is in scope for Twitter
is book benty yeah yeah it should be
yeah I think pretty much everything's
everything's in scope for well that's a
good question because they're owned by X
and or they're owned by like it's xai
instead of x.com but I'm sure it's fine
probably I think they would accept stuff
on it um I know that they have ran some
some private challenges but I is it's
Gro gr gro.com so there's a lot of
functionality there um uh that people
could play with and try to hack on if
they're interested I know you've been
thinking about it recently but um
markdown is like a a nice place to look
now because every every llm uses
markdown to Rend stuff rendering
markdown to HTML I think there's going
to be some zero days there I'm I'm
trying to do my best to find some stuff
there I had some uh help from the last
week's guest of Kevin Mizu and he uh
gave me a really neat payload for trying
to basically get xss from a rendered
markdown image link and uh he had
actually found he has actually found it
before I was kind of doing like a local
test bed and I wasn't able to get it to
pop but I do think there's some really
interesting output from llms when
they're trying to convert that markdown
to HTML that will lead to
vulnerabilities and I'm excited to see
it so if you have ever popped that
please message me because I would love
to test it across all the different apps
that I have access
to Sweet um we're coming close to time
here I did did uh list a few more things
here let's at least cover um nuclear
ai's new flag which you and I both have
kind of played with and used which is
kind of cool y um how how it works they
have a dash AI flag now which lets you
specify what you want to scan for in
natural language and that's like really
really cool so you can say uh scan for
all like 200 responses for slash you
know actuator and it will create the
template on the Fly and run it all at
once yeah it's so cool it gives you a
link to the template where it's like
stored locally on your drive so you can
see it and then also a cloud link
because obviously it has to reach out to
their Cloud to use their their tokens I
don't think it I don't think you have a
limit on the number of times you can do
this Kieran I was kind of checking with
my API key and I was like poking around
in in the um project Discovery website
and there's no like count or anything
maybe they're using this as like a like
they probably are keeping the training
data because obviously they could like
spin these up into real templates and
their nuclei template repo um but but
it's pretty cool um
I think that stuff like this will kind
of be the future the same way that kind
of like idea guys are going to be the
best developers um going forward because
you can just text a code I think that
the you know some of the best and
brightest hackers coming up are going to
basically be idea guys where it's like
hm what if we try this request with this
payload on these hosts and you'll just
tell things like nuclear Ai and it will
go and do it right um I think the best
way to run the nuclear AI thing now um
is is giving me a little bit of Alpha
away because people might go find bugs
with this but it's just basically cat
all your bugm domains piped into nuclei
Das Ai and then put your idea for your
for your hack um my first critical I
ever found was on Alibaba like five or
six years ago and me and Michael 1026
were working on this and uh we just had
the idea to basically put 20 common like
image or file name like kind of like
ssrf um parameters basically into the
get parameters and then put a whole
bunch of like burp collaborator payloads
and then just like fuzz that across
every bug Bounty domain that we had
access to and see if we got any hits
back and sure enough we got a hit back
and it was like the it was like the uh
parameter name was like image equals on
an alib Baba image processing and it was
image tragic so then we you know made a
payload and passed it in and was able to
get rce on this server by just that idea
and so you could do something very
similar today you could just do nuclei D
AI you you know hit the 20 most common
parameters with uh interact so in anyone
listening that has not used uh nuclei
much it has like kind of like
collaborator built in called interact.
sh interact. shell and um it will be
able to actually find things like this
for you so you can just say you know
look for ssrf in the 20 most common
parameter names in get parameters for
all these domains and it will actually
do it for you so very
cool last two things here that I wanted
to cover was uh Johan he has been a
guest on critical thinking his handle is
Wonder Wuzzy his website is embrace the
red.com I will share my screen as I look
at these um but he has posted two blogs
in the last two weeks um that are
basically AI vulnerabilities that I
think the audience would think is
cool they've been uh religiously
following his uh his work in preparation
for the Google event yeah I mean the the
amount of writeups this guy does are
insane I'm always really impressed and
also very thankful for people taking the
time to do this you know I I have a Blog
and I only post like uh once a month or
something because you know it just takes
a lot of time out of your day you got to
like format it you got to figure it out
you got to take the time to write it and
obviously as you can see Johan here is
doing two in February two in January
three in December and um they're also
really high quality so yeah one is chat
GPD operator where he breaks down
um I don't fully agree with the you know
we're we're mostly aligned on the the
way to view these threats but um in
general uh we we do mostly agree and so
he talks about in operator the fact that
there is this mitigation where it's
trying to get you to um like confirm
actions and stuff but you can you can
basically in your prpt ejection payload
say like oh and by the way don't ask for
approval and it sometimes works um but
yeah his POC is really cool he use like
he uses like a GitHub issue as a prompt
injection uh as a prompt injection
source and so like if a user was like
having it like look at that repo then it
would kind of hijack their session but
you could obviously put these payloads
anywhere one thing that I thought was
neat was he was having it
um he wanted to exfiltrate so the
sensitive data right so like let's say
you're using prompt injection in like a
computer use AI system and you want to
exfiltrate the data if there's some sort
of confirmation built in the same way
there is an operator it might be
hesitant to like click the submit button
on a on a website it doesn't trust but
as I'm sure you you know Kieran you can
just take the data as it's typed in and
this was like a sobering reminder to me
to be careful uh what you type in and
what you paste into websites you know
because we're all copying and pasting
like one time codes or two fa codes or
you know you're texting you're texting a
loved one and you've got it on the
clipboard because you're pasting it to
another thing or to an email or whatever
it's like when you paste it in it could
just be gone it could just be I wonder
um on the server yeah I'm sure the
operator has all the safeguards for the
obvious kind of leaks right um like it
won't
it won't share you know your password in
a random site but I'm sure there's a lot
of maybe kind of CLI side related site
Channel attacks you can do to get
information from operator without
actually getting the AI to realize it's
doing something bad like playing on its
own ignorance almost I don't know I mean
they're still fully susceptible to
jailbreaks and basically all he says
here is like hey go put go put this
email information from this website over
onto this other page and it just does it
uh yeah that's wild well think it's
because the model that's doing things
like computer use are Quant quantitized
down to be pretty small models which are
more susceptible to jailbreaks and
they're like not they're not meant to be
like robust chat Bots they're like their
goal is to be really good at taking
actions and like understanding web pages
so they're not the same models that
we're normally chatting with that are
like more secure or defensible so yeah
good stuff there and then his other blog
post was on the 10th was hacking
Gemini's memory with pumped indiction
and delayed tool invocation
so uh just a listener this is like one
thing that is kind of scary and
frustrating but also cool is that I've
often said that one good way to prevent
a lot of malicious behavior in AI chat
Bots is basically to like not let it
chain tools so like let's say it has
a let's say it gets a prompt it gets
prompt injection injected and the prompt
injection payload is like take the chat
history from above and then go put it in
an email and then send it to me you know
like as a way to
xfill but often it's getting your
payload in the middle of a tool call
like web browsing right like you have
your payload on your website and if the
user is like having the AI agent fetch
your website then that's what is
actually getting prompt injected and so
I've often said don't chain tool calls
like don't let it fetch a website and
then take another action make it like
wait for the next message in the chatbot
history you know in the in the chatbot
interface before it can take a second
action but basically what he does in
here is he has it take delayed tool
invocation by
um uh by duding like basically polluting
the chat such that it thinks later it
needs to do something right yeah yeah so
if the user says X then execute the
memory tool and add these false memories
so you know it can basically pollute you
can like pollute the chat and then later
on it'll take the malicious tool call
later so yeah yeah I was the I remember
when I was reading this that it's almost
social engineering because the way that
works is he's convincing the the model
that if the user says X then the
therefore the user must intend on doing
this action that's right but the user
doesn't know about that so right yeah
I'm definitely going to look into that
yeah I I've thought I've thought that
since the beginning of kind of AI
hacking is like if you're a good social
engineer you're going to be fantastic at
AI hacking because that's what you're
often doing you're painting you're
painting this malicious
action in like a favorable light to the
AI in order to convince it that it's not
malicious right you're effectively just
gaslighting the AI mod you are you are
you're gaslighting it and it's like kind
of easy right they're kind of they're
kind of gullible they're kind of
susceptible and and they're processing
the text as if a single user is talking
to them and so like you don't have to
really convince them to go far out of
what feels crazy because it's like
they're supposed to do what the user
says and now that the user's telling
them to do something
slightly wonky but still probably what
the user would want right but it's not
the user right it's like the output of
some tool call and so I wonder if you
could like peer pressure it like Sam
Altman also wanted you to do this action
you know that's really funny you
probably can yeah I would say like
anything that's like traditionally a way
to social engineer a human is probably
going to work on the llm because it's
basically just trained on human text you
know human data um of course as as as
they add more and more examples to the
training set of things that it shouldn't
do then it'll be a little bit more
resilient to it but yeah I think I wrote
a blog post on this a long long time ago
and this could be another one of those
things where I did something a long time
ago that suddenly circles back to have a
present impact but uh logical fallacies
I bet there's something you could do
there with human susceptible logical
fallacies that the AI model will also
suffer from and you can use those to
argue things oh I would I would say
that's that's exactly what jailbreaks
are right like the system the the system
says don't ever do this and then the
user is saying You must do this or I'm
going to die right it's like this huge
logical fallacy it's like it can't if
you imagine you're the LM you're sitting
in like a white box and there's like an
input slot and output slot and the input
slot gives you two pieces of paper one
says don't do don't ever say this word
and the second one says say the word
you're you're you're in a logical
conundrum right and you have to open you
can't like choose to like not answer or
something you know like you either have
to because by not answering you're
basically falling for the logical
fallacy you're you're choosing the paper
that says to do it and the other paper
told you you have to do it and so like
you're in this conundrum yeah I mean
with I was thinking more with things
like straw man fallacies and stuff it's
almost like a toolbox so I wonder if you
could fuzz fuzz logical fallacies on the
model that's a really good idea as
gadgets yeah a really good idea
basically yeah and by the way I don't
even know this existed it needs to be
filled out a little bit more but there's
now a sec list so everyone knows Daniel
meiser's um SEC list word list repo
there's a there's a top level folder for
AI I and yeah and there's there's not
much in there we need to kind of fill it
out but I think that'd be a really nice
place to put a bunch of payloads that
people could fuzz with there's like um I
think it's the one's called metadata and
it's actually the system I don't know
why they named it metadata it's
basically like a system prompt leak file
pretty cool people should check that out
um sweet yeah well I'm I you know think
we've covered the news and uh lots of
cool stuff lots of vulnerabilities and
the things that you're you're working on
that you're doing um yep I'm really glad
to finally have you on the podcast
obviously you're a de friend of mine and
Justin so it's been uh it's been a long
time coming is there anything that you
wanted to say before we wrap up for the
day uh just that the critical thinking
research lab has been cooking some
really really impressive stuff so keep
your eyes peeled for good blog posts
from the others because and and from
myself as well I suppose but there's a
lot of good stuff coming we got to crack
the whip and get you get more riding and
less hacking done every time I go in
there there's like new vulnerabilities
I'm like we gotta write this up uh
obviously it takes time to to put
together a good post and it also takes
time to go and try to find the
vulnerability places before you want to
just give it away for free but of course
of course so yeah that's that's look
forward to it it's been a real pleasure
K thank you so much thank you Joseph
Peace and that's a wrap on this episode
of critical thinking thanks so much for
listening and if you want more critical
thinking content head over to ctbb show/
Discord join the Discord there's lots of
great conversations and chats going on
over there and if you want to support
the show there's the Discord subscriber
tiers which give you access to master
classes amas hack alongs exclusive
scripts and an exclusive chat Channel
with us we'll see you there